Guide to the Ezra Stiles College, Yale University, Records of the Master
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Master of Ezra Stiles College, Yale University, records
1945-1975
RU 797
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
(2 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, minutes, and letters of recommendation maintained by Richard B. Sewall as master of Ezra Stiles College, Yale University.
Ezra Stiles College (Yale University)
Sewall, Richard B., 1908-2003
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 13-M-2 (YRG 13-M-2), Records of the master of Ezra Stiles College.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from Ezra Stiles College, 1979.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, minutes, and letters of recommendation maintained by Richard B. Sewall as master of Ezra Stiles College, Yale University.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
The title "Master" for chief executive officers of residential colleges was changed to "Head of College" in April of 2016.
College students; Student housing; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Ezra Stiles College (Yale University); Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Student housing; Yale University -- Students
- Correspondence, circa 1945-1975; Accession 1979-A-047
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research. Box 1 folders 17-21 are restricted.
  - Dorchester Abbey, England, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hampshire College, Conference on Residential Housing, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Language tests, Ph.D., student papers, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1945-1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Restricted until January 1, 2035.
  - Letters of recommendation, 1946-1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Restricted until January 1, 2040.
  - Letters of recommendation, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Restricted until January 1, 2041.
  - Letters of recommendation, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Restricted until January 1, 2042.
  - New York Times, letter to the editor, 1965, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Nuggets, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Orals and dissertations, notes (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Political, McCarthy, Vietnam, speech at teach in, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Reading lists, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Reading lists, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Santa Cruz, University of California at, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Secondary schools, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Stiles College Mastership, personal correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Transitional Year Program (T.Y.P.), 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Upward Bound, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Vietnam, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Yale Summer High School (Y.S.H.S.), minutes, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Yale Summer High School and the Yale Daily News, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 44)